I want to show you how I can build
slide decks using Cloud.
We'll also use Gemini as part of the process
to be able to create a short video tutorial that you can add to your e-learning.
So,
I'm going to add in my query here and I will share the query
uh
later,
but you can see here,
I've got
all the basic parts of the query.
I'm an instructional designer.
I need you to create 3 slides
that explain how an API sends a request and gets a response for data.
And I'm telling it the color scheme to use,
tea,
white and black.
And then I've got the title slide,
and then
I'm telling them what to do on each one of the slides.
So,
go ahead and we'll submit that request.
And now you can see,
the slide deck has been rendered.
With those requirements.
And on the top right,
I can download this
as a presentation.
I'm going to move this into Drive.
Now that we're in Google Slides,
we're going to transform this presentation
into a video.
So click on the transform button on the right-hand side.
So turned into a video.
It's asking me which slides to select,
so you can make a decision there.
And additionally,
you can decide whether or not to put the music or not.
And,
uh,
it is not a hard choice right now.
I'm going to leave that because you can edit that later.
For example,
if you don't like the music,
you can remove it.
Maybe you like the music,
but not that song.
You can
Uh,
change the song.
Now,
this is actually probably the most important part is to review the text.
Each one of the slides,
it has automatically created text for you.
And you have a choice to make a change,
uh,
on this,
and that's typically what I do is I update these
to
reflect what I really want because sometimes I find it's a bit too generic.
I just made those changes there.
Similarly,
I'd go through all the other ones and do that.
Additionally,
I can modify who is speaking.
So,
I'll go ahead and uh change this to educator.
Now,
you can also create your own voice.
There is a function to
have your own voiceover and that works as well.
I'm just going to use the automated
feature just so you understand what's available,
and I'm going to create the draft video.
So,
now the draft video is created.
You can click on play.
Now,
I'm just going to
go to the bottom here.
There
is this music,
corporate technology innovation,
right.
OK.
So that can be
deleted.
That can be
changed to a different song.
You can edit that.
So,
you have full control over that.
On the right-hand side here,
uh,
you'll see voiceover,
so you can create your own voiceover if you prefer.
Uh,
on this,
uh,
in the.
Video functionality.
And we'll just go ahead and play briefly.
We will review how a smartphone application
communicates to the cloud through the API.
It starts when your app sends a request to the server.
This acts like a
OK.
So,
now that is completed.
I'm gonna show you one more thing
that we're going to add.
Typically,
on these training videos,
you have a
2 to 5 2nd
intro that's consistent across your videos for your branding.
So,
I'm gonna show you how you can use
Gemini
to build that and then insert that in here.
Now in Gemini,
so we're going to
create a.
4 2nd
intro.
Video.
With music
and
use the title.
Learn
With
APIs
uh in.